Guide to the Richard Bruce Nugent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Long works of fiction, novels, 1929-1985; Series III; (18 boxes)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "First Meeting with Dude (Dudric Dramulian)," pp. 1-12., ca 1970s; 12 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections on the verso of "The Polyglot Company" letterhead. (Box 41)
    Ajpparently complete
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Sheik's Visit to Onesto in N.Y. Before He Returns to Iran," pp. 1-5., ca 1970s; 5 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections on the verso of "The Polyglot Company" letterhead. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Augie & Oberon," pp. 1-3, ca 1970s; 3 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Kevin & Oberon" (2 Versions), Unpaginated; pp. 1-8, ca 1970s; 7 leaves + 8 leaves. Ribbon copies with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Both versions complete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. " Oberon & Kiley [Kevin] ( First Encounter)" pp. 1-5., ca 1970s; 5 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. " Kiley [Kevin] & Oberon (Second Encounter)" pp. 1-6., ca 1970s; 6 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Apparently complete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. " Oberon & Kiley [Kevin] (Second Encounter)" pp. 1-9., ca 1970s; 8 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Apparently complete, despite the absence of p. 2. Perhaps the pages were mis-numbered.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Kiley & Oberon (Third Encounter)" pp. 1-9; Oberon & Kiley (Third Encounter), pp. 1-3; 2 odd leaves, ca 1970s; 15 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Narratives apparently complete despite the presence of the oddleaves.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Kiley & Oberon (Fourth Encounter)" pp. 1-6; "Oberon & Kevin (Fourth Encounter)," 3 odd leaves, ca 1970s; 9 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    The three odd leaves are entitled "Oberon and Kevin: (fourth encounter - part 1)" "Oberon and Kevin: (fourth encounter - Anthony)" "Kevin Kiley and Oberon" (fourth encounter)"
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Sylvio & Oberon," pp. 1-9., ca 1970s; 9 leaves. Ribbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Sally & Oberon," pp. 1-2; "Ronny & Oberon & Sally," pp. 1-3; "Oberon & Sally (2)," 2 pages., ca 1970s; 7 leaves. Ribbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Stavo," pp. 1-3, ca 1970s; 3 leaves. Ribbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "On Meeting Menachem," pp. 1-2; "On Meeting Oberon: Menachem," p.1; "Moishe & Oberon," 1 page., ca 1970s; 4 leaves. Ribbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. [Cippie (Cipriano)], pp. 1; 1-4; 4-12, ca 1970s; 14 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    3 separate segments. Incomplete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. [Pat], pp. 1-32; 1-3, ca 1970s; 35 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    2 separate segments. Incomplete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. [Gino (Guido)], pp. 1-7; [1-3]; 1-4, ca 1970s; 14 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    3 separate segments. Apparently complete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Meeting Mauro; One Year After," pp. 1-20, ca 1970s; 20 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Birthday. On A Hot Night in April" [Mauro], pp. b-e, ca 1970s; 4 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. [Danny], ca 1970s; 2 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Gerry & Oberon," Unpaginated, ca 1970s; 4 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Possibly complete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Gerry & Oberon (first time after Dubie and him)," pp. 1-11; "Gerry & Oberon (2) (1st time after Dubie)," pp. 1-6; "Oberon & Jerry," pp. 1-4., ca 1970s; 23 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Includes 2 odd leaves relating to Jerry. Otherwise, apparently complete.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. [Philly], ca 1970s; 29 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 41)
    Several incomplete segments and odd pages relating to Philly/Fabio.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. Miscellaneous Odd Pages, ca 1970s; ca. 29 leaves. (Box 41)
  - THIS IS THE DAY. Notes, ca 1970s; ca. 10 leaves. (Box 41)
  - URANUS IN CANCER, ca. 1955-1965 (Box 42)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft I, pp. 1-143. "Esposition;" "Lunatique;" "Letters into Limbo, ca. 1955-1965; 142 leaves. Ribbon copy with a very few holograph corrections. (Box 42)
    Missing p.116. Otherwise, Draft I is apparently complete, consecutively numbered from beginning to end, except as noted below.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft I, pp. 144-160; 170-252, ca. 1955-1965; 100 leaves. (Box 42)
    Despite missing pp. 161-169, there is no break in the narrative. It appears that there is simply a mistake in pagination.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft II, pp. 1-166. "Exposition;" "Lunatique;" "Letters into Limbo, 1959; Ca. 177 leaves. Ribbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 42)
    P. 123 supplied from the carbon. Incomplete. There are 16 "Letters into Limbo;" Letters 13-16 are not included in Draft I.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft II, pp. 1-166. "Exposition;" "Lunatique;" "Letters into Limbo, 1959; Ca. 177 leaves. Carbon copy. (Box 43)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft III, [Letter # 6 of "Letters into Limbo"], Unpaginated., ca. 1955-1965; 10 leaves. (Box 43)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft IV, "Lunatique," pp. 1-21., ca. 1955-1965; 22 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 43)
    Includes an odd page from another draft.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft V, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 2-85., ca. 1955-1965; 84 leaves. Carbon copy with a few holograph corrections. (Box 43)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft V, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 86-160., ca. 1955-1965; 74 leaves. Carbon copy with very few holograph corrections. Missing p. 150. (Box 43)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft V, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 13-49; 32-40., ca. 1955-1965; 46 leaves. (Additional carbon copies.) (Box 43)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VI, "Letters into Limbo." pp. 37-178, ca. 1955-1965; 142 leaves. Carbon copy. (Box 44)
    Letters # 5 - 13.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VI, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 179-273 finis., 95 Leaves. Carbon copy. (Box 44)
    Letters # 14-19.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VI, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 43-49; 180-196; 198-209; 211-222; 224-246; 250-260; 263-272, ca. 1955-1965; 92 leaves. (Extra carbons.) (Box 44)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VII, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 1-42., ca. 1955-1959; 42 Leaves. Ribbon copy on tanned, acidic paper. Some pages chipped. (Box 44)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VII, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 43-63; 81-119; 110-135; 126-135, ca. 1955-1959; 96 Leaves. Ribbon copy on tanned, acidic, fragile paper. Some pages chipped. (Box 45)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VII, "Letters into Limbo," pp. 171-251., ca. 1955-1959; 81 Leaves. Ribbon copy on tanned, acidic, fragile paper. Some pages chipped. (Box 45)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft VIII, "Sing A Dream," Unpaginated., ca. 1955-1965; ca. 77 leaves. Ribbon copy. 10 multi-page segments and 2 single pages with gaps. (Box 45)
    The supplied page numbers are keyed to Draft I.
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Draft IX, "Sing A Dream," Unpaginated., ca. 1955-1965; ca. 17 leaves. Ribbon copy. 4 multi-page segments with gaps. (Box 45)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. "Exposition," "Lunatique," "Letters into Limbo," Odd Manuscript Pages, ca. 1955-1965; ca 32 leaves. (Box 45)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. "Sing a Dream," Odd Typescript Pages & Segments, ca. 1955-1965; ca 52 leaves (Box 45)
  - URANUS IN CANCER. Notes, ca. 1955-1965; ca 6 leaves (Box 45)
- Documentation of Nugent's career, 1927-2009; Series IV; (1 box)
  - Gallery M, 2003; 4 Items (Box 46)
    Materials relating to the exhibit: postcard announcement, flyers, list of items on exhibit. Artists: Aaron Douglas, Bruce Nugent, Malick Sidibe. Feb 8-March 8.
  - Harlem Cultural Council, 1966; 2 Items (Box 46)
  - Henry Street Settlement Playhouse, [1974]; 1 Items (Box 46)
    Program for the play "Candidate" by Charles Fuller, in which Nugent appeared in a minor role.
  - Hofstra University, 1985; 4 Items (Box 46)
  - Leslie/Lohman Gay Art Foundation, 2006; 1 Item (Box 46)
    Announcement card. Other artists in the exhibition: Duncan Grant, Celso Castro, Eric Rhein. This was the first Nugent retrospective in NYC.
  - OutCharlotte 2000, 7 Items (Box 46)
  - Pen Oakland Josephine Miles Award, 2009; 2 Items (Box 46)
    Certificate presenting the award to Nugent for GENTLEMAN JIGGER & a brochure containing biographical sketches of Nugent and the other winners.
  - Plexus, 1984-86; 6 Items (Box 46)
    Materials relating to Plexus/ Shuttle Theatre. Nugent participated in the 1985 "Purgatorio '85" show at C. U. A. N. D.O. on July 17, 1985, appearing in a tableux as the Pope.
  - Porgy, 1927-1929; 7 Items (Box 46)
  - Run, Little Chillun!, 1933; 2 Items (Box 46)
    Program & flyer for Hall Johnson's play, in which Nugent danced. The flyer (for the Garrick Theatre in Philadelphia) reproduces the review of the play in Literary Digest, April 15, 1933.
  - Schomburg Center, 2004; 4 Items (Box 46)
    Materials relating to the 4/18/2004 panel discussion of Nugent in which Samuel R. Delany, Abba Elethea,, David Levering Lewis, Robert Reid-Pharr, Margaret Rose Vendryes & Wirth participated.
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, 2003; 1 Item (Box 46)
    Sims, Lowery Stokes. The Challenge of the Modern: African American Artists 1925-1945. NY: Studio Museum in Harlem, 2003. The exhibition contained works from all the major African Artists of the period; Nugent's works are prominently featured.
  - Temple Emmanu-El Festival of the Arts, 1965; 5 Items (Box 46)
    Exhibition listing, poster, and associated correspondence. Included with Nugent were many prominent African American artists.
- Personal, family, and finanical papers, 1906-1990; Series V; (4 boxes)
  - Personal, Family, and Financial Papers (Box 47)
  - Addresses, ca 30 items (Box 47)
    Miscellaneous notes & documents with addresses of Nugent & others
  - Addresses: Address Books, 4 Address Books (Box 47)
  - Addresses: Business Cards, ca 100 Items (Box 47)
  - Addresses: File, ca 60 Items (Box 47)
    Pages from a "Rolodex"-type file
  - Ancestry: Robinson Essays, 5 Items (Box 47)
    4 essays about the Bruce family by Henry S. Robinson, a distant cousin of Nugent's, with an announcement of the Hannah Bruce Bicentennial.
  - Ancestry: Wirth Research, 11 Leaves (Box 47)
    Photocopies & notes from Ancestry.com & the U.S. Census
  - Arnstein, Daphne, 1975; 2 Items (Box 47)
    Contract and note regarding Nugent's marijuana-leaf tee-shirt design.
  - Art: Japanese Dyes, 1 Item (Box 47)
    Sample booklet for Nicholson''s Peerless Japanese Transparent Water Colors
  - Astrology/Spirituality/Self Help, Numerous Items (Box 47)
    2 "Personal Biorythm Forecasts" for Nugent; miscellaneous other personalized materials & notes in Nugent's hand.
  - Astrology/Spirituality/Self Help, 5 Items (Box 48)
    Horoscopes
  - Autobiographical Notes, 7 Leaves (Box 48)
  - Birth Certificate, 1906; 2 Leaves (Box 48)
    Two official copies (1971, 1985)
  - BN Arts, 1965; 2 Items (Box 48)
    2 copies of BN Arts' business certificate
  - Calendars, 2 Items (Box 48)
    Engagement calendars, 1965 & 1976. Mostly unused.
  - Certificate of Alien Registration, 1929; 1 Item (Box 48)
    Issued during Nugent's trip to England with Porgy. Excellent photo of Nugent.
  - Christmas Cards (Unsent), 3 Items (Box 48)
    Signed "Bruce
  - Dunbar High School Transcript, 1919-1920; 1 Item (Box 48)
    Unofficial copy.
  - Edgeworth Industrial Supply (Nugent's Employer), 3 Items (Box 48)
  - Estate, 1987-1990; Numerous Items (Box 48)
    Financial records, notes, correspondence and other material relating to Nugent's estate.
  - Estate: McClendon Bust, 1987-1990; 9 Items (Box 48)
    Correspondence relating to Richmond Barthe's bust of Rose McClendon, which was inscribed "To Bruce" in the plaster and bequeathed by Nugent to his friend Raymond Jenkins, who in turn gave it to the Schomburg Center.
  - Food Stamps & Public Assistance, 1978-1987; Several Items (Box 48)
  - Financial: Forged Checks, 1983, 1985; Several Items (Box 48)
    Documentation relating to the forgery by William Jeter of Nugent's signature on Nugent checks
  - Financial: Income, 6 Items (Box 48)
  - Financial: Income Tax, 1985; 2 Item (Box 48)
    Tax Returns
  - Financial: Medicaid, 1978-1987 (Box 48)
  - Financial: Payments to Friends, 1978-1987; Numerous Items (Box 49)
    Canceled checks
  - Financial: Social Security, 1970-1987 (Box 49)
  - Financial: Unemloyment Benefits, 1942, 1972; Several Items (Box 49)
  - FIRE!! Press, 1982-1986; Several Items (Box 49)
    Author contract, publicity materials, "Lighting FIRE!!
  - Harlem Cultural Council, 2 Items (Box 49)
    Membership card; cancelled check
  - Hospitalization, 1987; 2 Leaves (Box 49)
    Notes by THW
  - Idendification & Membership Cards, 11 Items (Box 49)
  - Marr, Grace, Several Items (Box 49)
    Death certificate (suicide), Correspondence relating to Marr's TIAA death benefits, articles about Marr, Social Security card, etc.
  - Marr, Grace: Writings, 1950; 2 Items (Box 49)
    Diary entries
  - Memorial Service, 1987; Numerous Items (Box 49)
    Announcement, program, correspondence, notes, returned envelopes
  - Misc, 6 Items (Box 49)
  - Nugent, Pete, 4 Items (Box 49)
    Checks to Hotel Latham
  - Nugent, Pauline Minerva Bruce (Williams), Several Items (Box 49)
    Birth & death ceritifcates, bankbook, correspondence re hospitalization (mental), funeral home corresp
  - Nugent, Richard Henry, Jr., Several Items (Box 49)
    Death certificate, WW I Draft registration; 1910 Census entry
  - Obituaries, 1987; 3 Items (Box 49)
  - Passports & Photo ID, 1929-1981; 5 Items (Box 50)
    Passports, Immuniaztion Certificate, ID from Hudson County
  - Porgy Trip to England, 1929; 1 Item (Box 50)
    List of US Citizens arriving on the Majestic, June 12, 1929.
  - Portrait Sketches of Nugent, 4 Items (Box 50)
    Sketches on lightweight paper. 3 Signed. Signatures illegible.
  - Residence: 113 14th Street, Hoboken, 1977-1987; Voluminous File (Box 50)
    Rent checks, papers related to attempted eviction and appeal thereof. correspondence with landlord.
  - Studio: 163 East 118th Street, NYC, 1957-1959; 11 Items (Box 50)
    Complaint about loss of power
  - Studio Relocation: 99 Beekman St to 150 Nassau St., 1965-1966; ca 20 Items (Box 50)
    Correspondence with landlords, notices of late rent, application for relocation assistance, etc.
  - Studio-Residence: 150 Nassau St, 1966-1979; Several Items (Box 50)
    Rent checks, notices of rent due.
  - Telephone Numbers, Several Items (Box 50)
    Small file pages, notes
  - Travel, 1971-1973; 6 Items (Box 50)
    Receipts
  - Wills, 1978, 1985; 3 Items (Box 50)
  - Wirth, Thomas, Several Items (Box 50)
    Checks, power of attorney, etc. relating to financial matters.
  - WPA, 1939; 1 Item (Box 50)
    Notice of Termination of Employment
- Printed appearances of writings and art by Nugent, 1925-2009; Series VI; (3 boxes)
  - ... And More Gently Still, 1932; 1 Item (Box 51)
  - Christmas Cards, ca 1955; 2 Items (Box 51)
    Christmas cards designed by Nugent and published by House of Marr. One of the designs is "Frankincense," a drawing that appeared on the cover of the December 1971 issue of Crisis. Condition: near fine.
  - Dark Tower"; Illustration for "Whitewash" by John W. Vandercook, 1927; 1 Item (Box 51)
  - Illustration, 1927; 1 Item (Box 51)
    Opportunity, Volume 5, Number 8 (August, 1927). Defective copy, missing pp. 231-238. Inscribed to Wirth on p. 227 under the illustration: "For Tom -- epitome of many things of which I've spoken to him/ Bruce
  - Illustrations for "Black Studies Primer, 1969; 2 Items (Box 51)
    1. "Black Studies Primer," NY: NAACP, nd. 12mo pamphlet. 8 pp. Condition: fine. 2. NAACP check stub, payment for the illustrations."
  - Illustrations for "Negro Life in New York's Harlem" by Wallace Thurman, 1927; 1 Item (Box 51)
    Haldeman Julius Quarterly, Volume 2, Number 1 (October-November-December 1927). 4 half-page illustrations by Nugent. Condition: very good.
  - Illustrations for "One More Time, 2001; 1 Item (Box 51)
    Transition 89 (2001). 12 Nugent images accompany "One More Time," Brent Hayes Edwards's review of David Levering Lewis's biography of W. E. B. Du Bois. Condition: near fine
  - Interview with Bruce Nugent, 1982; 1 Item (Box 52)
  - Marshall's--A Portrait, 1944; 1 Item (Box 52)
    Phylon, Volume 5, Number 4 (Fourth Quarter 1944). Condition: Cover detached and partially mended with transparent tape, stains. Contents very good-fine.
  - Narcissus, 1933; 1 Item (Box 52)
  - The Now Discordant Song of Bells, 1989; Several Items (Box 52)
  - Pope Pius the Only, 1937; 1 Item (Box 52)
    Challenge, Volume 2, Number 1 (Spring 1937). Signed by Nugent on the front cover and on p. 15, where his story begins. Condition: Front cover partially detached; covers stained and soiled, contents very good.
  - Scheme, 1936; 1 Item (Box 52)
  - Shadow, 1925; 1 Item (Box 52)
    Opportunity, Volume 3, Number 34 (October 1925). SIGNED by Nugent on p. 296 where his poem appears. First publication of Nugent's work. Cover art by Aaron Douglas. Condition: very good-fine.
  - Smoke, Lilies and Jade, 1999; 2 Items (Box 52)
    The James White Review, Volume 16, Number 1 (Winter 1999). Introduction by Samuel R. Delany. Together with a letter of transmittal to Wirth.
  - Ganymede: Gay Men's Culture from New York. Issue 4 (June, 2009), Fine in wrappers. (Box 53)
    Reprints three chapters of Gentleman Jigger: "Niggeratti Castle," "Rent Party," and "Toothache." as well as "Drawings for Mulattoes--Number 4" and the cover of the March 1926 issue of The Crisis.
  - Johnson, Charles S., editor. Ebony and Topaz: A Collectanea. New York: National Urban League, 1927., Good in wrappers. Front hinge broken; backstrip crudely glued to page block. (Box 53)
    Inscribed on the last page under the illustration by Nugent: "For Tom Wirth -- a valuable friend / Bruce Nugent". Contains the 4-image series "Drawings for Mulattoes," with each image occupying a full page.
  - Harlem Heritage. Paris: Riveneuve Continents, 2008, Fine in wrappers. (Box 53)
    Contains "Richard Bruce Nugent: "Enfant Terrible" de la Renaissance de Harlem" by Thomas H. Wirth. "Drawings for Mulattoes -- Number 2" is reproduced on the cover.
- Drafts of and correspondence relating to posthumously published work by Nugent, 1995-2007; Series VII; (17 boxes)
  - Gay Rebel of the Harlem Renaissance, c1995-2002 (Box 54)
    Materials relating to the publication of Gay Rebel of the Harlem Renaissance by Duke University Press
  - Gay Rebel - Award Nominations, 2003; Several Items (Box 54)
    Materials relating to the Randy Shilts Award of The Publishing Triangle
  - Gay Rebel - Copyrights, 1 Item (Box 54)
    List of copyright holders of illustrations
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Akin, Wanda, 1998; 3 Items (Box 54)
    Notes by Wirth on marketing Gay Rebel
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Duke University Press, 1997-2001; Numerous Items (Box 54)
    Letters, enclosures, and email printouts
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Duke University Press, 2001; Numerous Items (Box 54)
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Duke University Press, 2001-2009; Numerous Items (Box 54)
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Duke University Press - Contract, 1999; Several Items (Box 55)
    Letters & email printouts involving negotiation of the contract to publish Gay Rebel.
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Gates, Henry Louis, 1996-2001; 3 Items (Box 55)
    Includes the typescript of the Foreword to Gay Rebel
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1996-1997; Numerous Items (Box 55)
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Oxford University Press, 1996-1998; Several Items (Box 55)
    Oxford considered and ultimately rejected Gay Rebel. Included is Bruce Kellner's highly negative reader's report.
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Permissions, 2000-2002; Numerous Items (Box 55)
    Permissions to publish copyrighted material in Gay Rebel.
  - Gay Rebel - Correspondence - Response to Publication, 2002; Numerous Items (Box 56)
  - Gay Rebel - Publicity, 2002-2003; Numerous Items (Box 56)
  - Gay Rebel - Reviews, 2002-2004; Numerous Items (Box 56)
  - Gay Rebel - Preliminary Typescripts - Copies With Corrections, 3 Items (Box 57)
    1. Salt Lake City Saga 2. I Am Twenty Five 3. You See, I Am A Homosexual
  - Gay Rebel - Synopsis, 3 Items (Box 57)
    Drafts of a Synopsis
  - Gay Rebel - Draft Manuscript, August 1996; 1 Item (Box 57)
  - Gay Rebel - Introduction - Draft - Holograph, 1 Item (Box 58)
  - Gay Rebel - Introduction - Drafts, 1996; 5 Items (Box 58)
  - Gay Rebel - Introduction - Drafts, 1996; 4 Items (Box 58)
    1. Undated draft with corrections by Wirth 2. Draft dated 10/9/96 3. Undated draft 4. Draft dated 11/16/96.
  - Gay Rebel - Introduction - Final Draft, 1 Item (Box 58)
    Typeset with illustrations.
  - Gay Rebel - Typed Nugent Materials - Wirth Corrections, 1 Item (Box 59)
  - Gay Rebel - Typeset Draft, 1 Item (Box 59)
    Parts of the typeset manuscript, with corrections by Wirth
  - Gay Rebel - Typeset Draft, 1 Item (Box 59)
  - Gay Rebel - Typeset Manuscript Submitted to Duke, 1 Item (Box 59)
  - Gay Rebel - Typeset Manuscript, Fall 2000; 1 Item (Box 60)
  - Gay Rebel - Offprint of Duke Manuscript - Part I, 2000; 1 Item (Box 61)
    Prepared by Duke in its editorial format
  - Gay Rebel - Offprint of Duke Manuscript - Part II, 2000; 1 Item (Box 61)
  - Gay Rebel - Offprint of Duke Manuscript - Part III, 2000; 1 Item (Box 61)
    Illustrations
  - Gay Rebel - Offprint of Duke Manuscript - Part I, June 2001; 1 Item (Box 62)
  - Gay Rebel - Offprint of Duke Manuscript - Part II, June 2001; 1 Item (Box 62)
  - Gay Rebel - Copyedited Manuscript to Duke, 2001; 1 Items (Box 63)
    1. Copyedited manuscript with Wirth response to copyeditor & corrections (October 2001)
  - Gay Rebel - Index (by Wirth), 2001; 1 Item (Box 63)
  - Gentleman Jigger, c2004-2009 (Box 64)
    Materials relating to the publication of Gentleman Jigger by Da Capo Press.
  - Gentleman Jigger - Contract, 2007; Several Items (Box 64)
    Executed contract with Avalon Publishing Group with preliminary draft and associated correspondence
  - Gentleman Jigger - Correspondence, 2006-2007; Numerous Items (Box 64)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Correspondence, 2007-2009; Numerous Items (Box 64)
    Correspondence with Bill Strachan & Adelaide Docx of Perseus & others involved in the publication and promotion of the book
  - Gentleman Jigger - Publicity, 2008; Several Items (Box 64)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Reviews, 2008-2009; Numerous Items (Box 64)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Preliminary Collection of Materials, Several Items (Box 65)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Incomplete Draft, 1 Item (Box 65)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Part I, 1 Item (Box 66)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Part II, 1 Item (Box 66)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Notes, 2004; Several Items (Box 66)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript Part 1, January 2007; 1 Item (Box 67)
    First completely typed printout, sans introduction & foreword
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Part II, January 2007; 1 Item (Box 67)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Part I, September 2007; 1 Item (Box 68)
    Complete typed printout, including the introduction & foreword
  - Gentleman Jigger - Manuscript - Part II, September 2007; 1 Item (Box 68)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Proofs - Part I, October 2007; 1 Item (Box 69)
  - Gentleman Jigger - Proofs - Part II, October 2007; 1 Item (Box 69)
  - Gentleman Jigger -- Manuscript with Corrections by Don Weise, July 2007; pp 1-174 (Box 70)